SEBASTIAN MANTILLA

SUMMARY

Sebastian Mantilla is a technology enthusiast, entrepreneur and information technologies professional, specialized in the development of complex, corporate applications and infrastructure. He has an integral vision of the technical, business and human aspects of the work at hand. He has extensive experience administering IT projects using agile methodologies. Committed to the highest professional and human standards. With a track-record that demonstrates he has the talent, education, and experience necessary to create teams, processes, and programs that simultaneously raise quality and lower costs in IT departments and consulting organizations. He is used to managing IT Infrastructure, no matter how complex it is, in a way that provides high availability, flexibility and cost effective solutions and services to users, institutions and companies.

Vertical Markets: Web Hosting, managed services.

Specialties: Server management, Web Development, Content Management Systems (CMS), eCommerce.

- Developed more than a 100 websites.
- Helped grow traffic to customer's sites by 10x.
- Increased customer's sales 20% using PPC campaigns.
- Optimized websites for Google using SEO reaching #1 spot for valuable keywords.

EXPERIENCE

2007-Present Greater Vancouver Systems

North Vancouver, BC

Director

- Quote, negotiate and provision servers for company and customers use.
- Create, manage and optimize PPC campaigns for customers.
- Build and manage mailing lists for email marketing.
- Install, configure, fine tune and monitor servers for the services the company provides.
- Define and implement security policies and practices for the servers under the company management.
- Identify, address and supervise reliability bottle necks such as performance, load or traffic.
- Write monitoring scripts that trigger alarms and initiate self-healing and recovery processes.
- Perform root cause analysis and develop checklists and solutions for typical problems.
- Recommend procedures and controls for problem prevention.

1996-Present Internet de Alta Calidad

Mexico city, Mexico

CEO

- Architect, code and implement and maintain web sites for the company and its customers.
- Define, implement and monitor digital strategies for the company and its customers.
- Implement eCommerce solutions using WordPress and WooCommerce.
- Implement eCommerce solutions using Drupal and Drupal Commerce.
- Provide infrastructure for virtual education using Moodle.

- Develop LAMP systems for the company and its customers.
- Create and interact with incidents on the company's internal ticketing system.
- Establish a VoIP network to support operations in Mexico.
- Compile, install and monitor Java based systems for GPS tracking, including both web based services and background data capturing processes.
- Provide desktop and remote support for different clients. Remote support provided through VNC, Windows Remote Desktop.
- Perform data backups and disaster recovery operations.

1996-2003 Banco del Bajio

Leon, Guanajuato, Mexico

Consultant

- Defined and implemented the Internet Banking platform.
- Planned and supervised the infrastructure for Internet Banking.
- Coordinated the definition of the infrastructure for Internet Banking from architecture, to servers
 including operating systems, QA practices, source control tools, servers installation, deployment and
 management.
- Personalized and built a custom Linux distribution for the Internet Banking platform including installation servers, web servers, database servers, DNS servers.
- 10x Internet Banking customer's growth.

EDUCATION

1989-1993 National Autonomous University of Mexico Mexico city, Mexico

B Sc Computer engineering

With Honours

1992-1993 National Autonomous University of Mexico Mexico city, Mexico

Supercomputing diploma

1999-2000 National Autonomous University of Mexico Mexico city, Mexico

Telecommunications diploma

2000 Gustav Käser Training International Mexico city, Mexico

Management

SKILLS

Sebastian Mantilla is an individual with the ability to adapt quickly to changing priorities, he can multitask, execute and plan strategies, work with all levels of management and also has analytical skills. He is computer literate and a creative thinker, he can also be deadline oriented with effective prioritization and time management skills, he is usually self-motivated and a team player.

Through his practice managing networks and servers he has become fluent in the installation, configuration and monitoring of services such as DHCP, DNS, FTP, SSH, email, firewalls, application firewalls, web servers, database servers (MySQL and PostgreSQL).

When developing applications he has used PHP, Java, HTML, CSS and Javascript to deliver functional and efficient solutions to business needs.

For his everyday activities he uses office suites such as Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, Power Point), Google Apps and Libre Office, in a way that it leverages all the functionality and benefits that each of them have.

MEMBERSHIPS

VanLug: Vancouver Linux Users Group, Vancouver Drupal Users Group, Ubuntu Canada, Ubuntu Vancouver LoCo, The Vancouver WordPress Meetup Group, VanDev: Vancouver's Software Developers Network, The Vancouver .netBC Users Group, Latincouver.

INTERESTS

Chess, reading, playing baseball, playing football, scuba diving.

REFERENCES

References are available on request.